Guide to the Irene Peslikis Papers, 1957-2002 and undated RL.01018
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1960-2002 and undated, 8 boxes
  - Notebooks and Journals, 1960-1984, 1992-2002 and undated
    - Loose leaf journal entries, undated (Box 15)
    - Loose leaf journal entries and draft of letter, undated (Box 15)
    - Notebooks, undated, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Notebooks, undated, 5 folders (Box 16)
    - Recipes, undated (Box 16)
- Personal Files, 1971-2000, 3 boxes
  Consists of files depicting the numerous financial, legal, and medical issues confronted by Peslikis over three decades. Peslikis received assistance in the form of SSI, food stamps, and subsidized housing for artists (at Westbeth Artist Housing), each of which required meticulous documentation in order to retain. Files are arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  A portion of the files in this series, as indicated below, are closed until 2099.
  - Apartment matters, 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Art sales, 1971, 1979, 1997-1999 (Box 17)
  - Artists' rights/art transfer agreements, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Bankruptcy, 1983-1989 (Box 17)
  - Boarder baby, 1987 (Box 17)
  - CAPS (Creative Artists Public Service) Program, 1975-1985 (Box 17)
  - Copyrights/patents, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Date books, 1969-2001, 5 of 6 folders (Box 17)
  - Date books, 1969-2001, 6 of 6 folders (Box 18)
  - Failed foot surgery, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Financial and related material, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Food stamps, 1986-1993, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Grant application materials, 1983-1990 (Box 18)
  - Letters from doctors re: disabilities, 1998-1999 (Box 18)
  - Lucia Vernarelli Hacker inheritance, 1994-1997 (Box 18)
  - Medicaid, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Medical reports, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Medical reports, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Notes, 199 Feb.-Mar. (Box 18)
  - Peslikis v. D'Agostino, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Pollock-Krasner Foundation, 1997, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Scooter accident, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
  - Supplemental Security Income (SSI), 1984-1986 (Box 19)
  - SSI, 1988-1993 (Box 19)
  - Sylvia G. Traube, M.D., 1989 (Box 19)
  - Westbeth, 1992-1994, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Westbeth recertification, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Westbeth recertification, 1987-1989 (Box 19)
  - Westbeth recertification, 1991-1993, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Westbeth recertification, 1996-1999 (Box 19)
  - Divorce and legal files, 1994-1999 (Box 20)
    These files are closed until 2099.
- Subject Files, 1964-1999 and undated, 7 boxes
  Consists primarily of clippings and notes retained by Peslikis on a number of women- and feminism-related subjects, as well as on art, astrology, United States foreign policy, and Greek politics. Subseries are arranged alphabetically.
  - Feminist Activism, 1966-1999 and undated
    Includes articles, notes, and event announcements related to various second and third wave feminist organizations, notes and research materials related to the first and second waves of the women's movement, and materials related to women's rights, women's health, the lesbian and gay rights movement, feminist theory, and sexuality.
    - Abortion (Box 21)
      - Pamphlets, articles on legislation, reproductive rights, and women's and religious views, 1969, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Abortion Action Panel, 1969 Feb.-Mar. (Box 21)
      - National Association for Repeal of Abortion Laws, 1969-1970 (Box 21)
      - Leaflets, articles on repeal of anti-abortion laws, 1969-1970 (Box 21)
      - Notes on reproductive rights and birth control, 1977 Oct. (Box 21)
      - No Restrictions!, speakout, 2000 (Box 21)
      - Leaflets on Women's liberation and welfare, undated (Box 21)
    - Association of Libertarian Feminists, 1973-1979 (Box 21)
    - Bread and Roses, conference on worker's culture, 1993 Dec. 11 (Box 21)
    - Congress to Unite Women, 1969 (Box 21)
    - Consciousness-raising, 1998-1999 (Box 21)
    - Equal Rights Amendment
      - Labor laws, 1970 (Box 21)
      - Action and follow-up, 1978 (Box 21)
      - National march, 1978 (Box 22)
      - Leaflets and list of sponsors, undated (Box 22)
    - The Feminist, articles by members, 1971 (Box 22)
    - Feminist Activism
      - Reports and notes, 1968-1999, 4 folders (Box 22)
      - Magazine clippings, 1969-1975 (Box 22)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1968-1970, 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Newsletters, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
      - Business letters, 1969-1971 (Box 22)
    - Feminist theory, commemorative conference, 1979 (Box 22)
    - Lesbian and Gay Rights Movement, 1970, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Male liberation and socioeconomic formations, 1973 (Box 23)
    - Marxist feminist group, 1975-1977 (Box 23)
    - Marxist feminist conference materials, 1978-1979 (Box 23)
    - National Organization for Women, 1966-1969 (Box 23)
    - New York Radical Women, 1975-1977 (Box 23)
    - Oasis Oil, 1967 July-Dec. (Box 23)
    - Publishing: Groove Press, undated (Box 23)
    - Radical Feminist Organizing Committee, 1981 (Box 23)
    - Redstockings, 1969-1979, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Redstockings Anthology, articles for notes from the first and second year, 1968-1970, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Scum Manifesto, undated (Box 23)
    - Sisterhood is Powerful Inc., open report by Robin Morgan, 1974 (Box 23)
    - Women Against Government Surveillance, 1977 (Box 23)
    - Women Against Pornography, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Women and Art
      - Women in the Arts, 1971 (Box 23)
      - Art groups, manifestos, and reports, 1971-1972 (Box 23)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 23)
    - Women's Action Alliance, 1979 (Box 24)
    - Women's Health Movement, 1968 (Box 24)
    - Women's Labor, 1966-1978 (Box 24)
    - Women's Liberation
      - Queen's College, 1967-1970 (Box 24)
      - Conference, Chicago, IL, 1968 (Box 24)
      - Conference contacts, 1968 (Box 24)
      - New School Graduate Center conference, 1968 (Box 24)
      - Publications, 1968-1971 (Box 24)
      - Class-consciousness, Colorado Springs, 1969 (Box 24)
      - Leaflets, 1969-1972, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Bibliographies and resources, 1969-1974 (Box 24)
      - Resources and articles, 1971-1978, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Marriage, divorce, 1974 (Box 24)
      - Articles, 1978-1980 (Box 24)
      - News and Letters, 1978 (Box 24)
      - Notes, undated (Box 25)
      - Selected writings, undated (Box 25)
      - Self-defense, undated (Box 25)
      - Song sheets, undated (Box 25)
    - Women's Movement
      - 149th Anniversary of the Seneca Falls Women's Rights Convention of 1848, resolutions of 1997, undated (Box 25)
      - Notes on Five for Freedom, by Constance Buell Burnett (Box 25)
    - Veteran Feminists of America, 1996-1997 (Box 25)
  - General Files, 1964-1997 and undated
    Contains clippings and articles retained by Peslikis on a number of subjects of interest to her beyond feminism, incuding art, astrology, and Greece.
    - The art establishment, 1970-1978 (Box 25)
    - Art in schools, including newspaper clipping on Peslikis, 1971-1998 (Box 25)
    - Artists Group, 1970 (Box 25)
    - Astrology
      - Notes on horoscopes and article, 1984-1985 (Box 25)
        [Note: Includes photographs of Peslikis in China and Russia.]
      - Finished horoscope charts, sketches, 1985 Mar.-June (Box 25)
      - Horoscope calculations, 1985-1986 (Box 25)
      - Natal horoscope and words of comfort, 1991 Oct.-1992 Jan. (Box 25)
      - New York School of Astrology announcement, horoscope descriptions, and articles, undated (Box 25)
    - Conferences and panels, 1972-1976 (Box 25)
      [Note: Item removed to Oversized Materials.]
    - Cultural control in the visual arts, workshops, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Angela Davis Festival of the Arts, undated (Box 25)
    - Ethnic heritage: Images of Immigrants Festival, Queens College, 1980 Apr. 26-27 (Box 25)
    - Film and Video
      - PBS controversy, 1979-1980 (Box 25)
      - Equipment rental and workshops, 1980 Mar.-June (Box 25)
    - Greece (Box 26)
      - Union of Greeks and Americans for Democracy, articles on foreign capital investment and women political prisoners, 1967-1972 (Box 26)
      - Articles, leaflets on fascist junta, notes for art exhibit, 1967-1971 (Box 26)
      - Issues of Demokratia on the execution of Mikis Theodorakis and The New York Review of Books, 1969 Apr.-1971 June (Box 26)
      - Foreign press, Mikis Theodorakis, and clippings from Demokratia, 1969 Oct.-1970 May (Box 26)
      - Pamphlets and articles on anti-imperialist activity; report of the First World Congress of Anti-Dictatorial Committees, 1969-1972 (Box 26)
      - Anti-dictatorial struggle, political cartoons, and draft of Peslikis's speech, 1970 (Box 26)
      - Community activism, leaflets, articles, 1970-1971 (Box 26)
      - Fascist rule and US involvement, 1970-1971 (Box 26)
      - Anti-dictatorial activity, reports, 1972-1974 (Box 26)
      - Cultural productions, 1973 (Box 26)
      - The Greek American Artists Projects, 1977 Mar. (Box 26)
      - Laography and Hellenic dances, undated (Box 26)
    - Hacker, Ernst and Lucia Vernarelli, Dahlias, undated (Box 27)
    - Hanisch, Carol, writings, events, correspondence, 1991-1997 (Box 27)
    - Karate, chart of basis techniques and notes, undated (Box 27)
    - Marriage, lecture material, 1977-1978 (Box 27)
    - Matisse, Henri, Retrospective Exhibition, Philadelphia Museum of Art, letter, 1948 (Box 27)
    - Millet, Kate, article, 1970 July (Box 27)
    - National Campaign for Tolerance, inscription of Peslikis's name on the Wall of Tolerance, 2002 June 28 (Box 27)
    - National Congress of Neighborhood Women, 1976 (Box 27)
    - New York Studio School, 1964-1966 (Box 27)
    - Photography
      - Class materials, undated (Box 27)
      - Negatives, undated (Box 27)
    - Professional interests, undated (Box 27)
    - Publicity, 1975-1979, Includes list of participants at the Lake Villa, IL Conference, Thanksgiving weekend, 1968, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Self-help resources, 1988 (Box 27)
    - The Society for the Study of Social Problems, thirtieth annual meeting, 1980 Aug. 23-26 (Box 27)
    - State University of New York College at Old Westbury, undated (Box 27)
    - Surrealist artists, articles and exhibitions, 1967-1970 (Box 27)
    - University budgets, article, 1994 (Box 27)
    - Women artists: articles, exhibits, performances, and workshops, 1972-1981 (Box 27)
    - Women in business, 1969 Aug.-1979 Oct. (Box 27)
    - Women's health, medical news, 1979 (Box 27)
    - Women writers, newspaper clippings, 1972-1978 (Box 27)
    - World Festival of Youth and Students, 1973 July-Aug. (Box 27)
    - Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association, 1966 (Box 27)
    - Youth festival, East Berlin, 1973 Aug. (Box 27)
- Education, 1957-2001, 4 boxes
  Composed of files documenting Peslikis as a student, an instructor, and an instructor in search of employment. All subseries are arranged chronologically.
  - Student Files, 1957-1982
    Contains school records, course work, and notes.
    - Richmond Hill High School, course work, 1957-1962, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - School records, and curriculum vitae, 1957-1983 (Box 28)
    - Course work and notes, Art History seminar, Queens College, 1970 (Box 28)
    - Senior project on cityscapes, 1971 Dec. (Box 28)
    - Course notes, Queens College, 1971-1972 (Box 28)
    - Course notes, Art and Society, Queens College, circa 1972 (Box 28)
    - Course notes, Queens College, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Application materials for graduate programs, 1981-1982 (Box 28)
    - City College of New York, Master of Fine Arts application materials, 1981-1982 (Box 28)
    - Graduate course work and notes, 1981-1982 (Box 28)
    - Course notes, Contemporary Art seminar, 1982 Mar.-Nov. (Box 28)
  - Teaching Files, 1969-2001
    Contains application materials (including curriculum vitae), teaching notes, and syllabi.
    - The Queens School, teaching appointment, 1969 June-1970 Apr. (Box 28)
    - Ramapo College of New Jersey, course in crafts, 1974 (Box 28)
    - Ramapo College of New Jersey, course in jewelry making, 1974 (Box 28)
    - State University of New York (SUNY) College at Old Westbury, teaching notes, American Studies course in Women and Art, 1973-1981, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - SUNY College at Old Westbury and College of New Rochelle, Women's Studies syllabi, 1974-1979, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - SUNY College at Old Westbury, Art History lecture notes and class schedule, 1975 Jan.-Apr., 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Teaching notes, Introduction to Art Making, 1976-1992 (Box 29)
    - SUNY College at Old Westbury, Introduction to Women's Studies, 1977-1978 (Box 29)
    - SUNY College at Old Westbury, teaching notes and xeroxes for Introduction to Women's Studies, 1977-1981, 3 folders (Box 29)
    - College of New Rochelle School of New Resources, teaching appointments and opening of Women's Center, 1978-1979 (Box 30)
    - New York Feminist Art Institute, two-year outline of course in Elemental Feminism and syllabus, 1978-1979 (Box 30)
    - SUNY College at Old Westbury, course in Women and Art, lecture materials, 1979 (Box 30)
    - SUNY College at Old Westbury, notes for course development, Visual Diaries and/or Visual Histories, 1979 Nov.-Dec. (Box 30)
    - SUNY College at Old Westbury, American Studies Department Women & Art workshop, 1980 May (Box 30)
    - City College of New York, presentation slides and notes, Autumn 1981 (Box 30)
    - City College of New York, teaching plans for drawing course, 1982 Feb.-Mar. (Box 30)
    - City College of New York, Visual Arts orientation, 1982 Feb.-May (Box 30)
    - Vermont College of Norwich University, 2001 (Box 30)
  - Job Search Files, 1973-1999
    Contains letters of inquiry and responses, teaching statements, application materials, and course and instructor evaluations.
    - Curriculum vitae, circa 1973-1999 (Box 30)
    - Responses to letters of inquiry, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Course and instructor evaluations, 1974-1986 (Box 30)
    - SUNY College at Old Westbury, appointment letters and contracts, 1974-1980 (Box 30)
    - Letters of recommendation, 1975-1994 (Box 30)
    - Letters of inquiry and responses, 1976 (Box 30)
    - Letters of inquiry and rejection, 1976-1985, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Course descriptions and syllabi, 1977 and undated (Box 31)
    - Applications materials and letters of inquiry, 1978-1983 (Box 31)
    - Teaching statements, 1983 and undated (Box 31)
    - Empire State College, application materials, 1983-1984 (Box 31)
    - Guggenheim fellowship application materials, 1984 (Box 31)
    - Hunter College, application letter, 1985 Mar. (Box 31)
    - Rejection letters, 1992 (Box 31)
    - Application materials and letters of inquiry, 1993 (Box 31)
    - Sarah Lawrence College application information, 1993 Jan. (Box 31)
    - College Art Association, 1993 Sept. (Box 31)
    - Vermont College of Norwich University, Artist-Teacher position, 1993-1999 (Box 31)
    - Farleigh-Dickinson University, 1994 (Box 31)
    - Rejection letters, 1994 (Box 31)
    - Application materials, 1994 Mar., 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Indiana University of Pennsylvania, application packet, 1994 Mar. (Box 31)
    - Bowling Green State University, 1999 (Box 31)
- Art, 1959-2001 and undated, 6 boxes
  Composed of artwork by Peslikis, duplications of her artwork, sketchbooks, and files related to her exhibits, including flyers, reviews, and catalogs. Materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Artist's proofs of etchings (Box 32)
  - Artist's proof, 1982 (Box 32)
  - Book illustrations (Box 32)
  - Charcoal, pen and ink, pencil drawings, and prints, undated, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Cloister, pastel, 1966 (Box 32)
  - Collages and photocollages (Box 32)
  - Conte crayon (Box 32)
  - Drawings, pencil and pen and ink (Box 32)
  - Exhibit files, 1975-2001, Folders 1-3 of 6 (Box 32)
  - Exhibit files, 1975-2001, Folder 4-6 of 6 (Box 33)
  - Film negatives from "Street Miracle," undated (Box 33)
  - Graphics, 1980-1991 and undated, Folders 1-4 of 5 (Box 33)
  - Idea scrapbook, 1959-1969, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Negatives, Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34)
  - Negatives, 15th Street apartment, Richard, Allen, and Pilar, Head, and Domestic Queen, Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34)
  - Nell Blaine, recent paintings, 1983 (Box 34)
  - Notes, 1978 and undated (Box 34)
  - Notes, 1980-1983 (Box 34)
  - Paintings (Box 34)
  - Photograph of artist Tedde Wisefield, undated (Box 34)
  - Photographs: black and white glossies, undated (Box 34)
  - Photographs of Peslikis paintings, undated, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Prints of photocollages, Noho Gallery exhibit, 1978 (Box 35)
  - Sketchbooks, 8 folders (Box 35)
  - Slides, Folders 1-14 of 27 (Box 36)
  - Slides, Folders 15-27 of 27 (Box 37)
  - Story panels, pen and ink, 1997 Nov. (Box 37)
  - Transparencies (Box 37)
  - Untitled (Box 37)
  - Watercolor, Maine, 1967 (Box 37)
  - Watercolor, Maine, 1974 (Box 37)
  - Watercolor, Sag Harbor, Helen and Roy, 1979 (Box 37)
  - Watercolor, Susquehana, PA, 1979-1980 (Box 37)
  - Watercolor, California, 1985 (Box 37)
  - Watercolor, pencil drawings, Colorado, 1987-1989 (Box 37)
  - Watercolor, 1988 July (Box 37)
  - Watercolor, undated (Box 37)
  - Slides, handmade glass slides for 1980 performance, 7 color slide boxes (Box 37)
  - Buttons (Box 37)
  - Acrylic, pen and ink, pencil drawings, prints, undated (Box OS 2)
  - Japan Peace Conference, undated (Box OS 2)
  - Watercolor, Maine, Summer 1967 (Box OS 2)
  - Watercolor, Sag Harbor, Helen and Roy, 1979 (Box OS 2)
  - Watercolor, pencil drawings, undated (Box OS 2)
  - Drawings undated (Box OS 3)
  - Drawings and paintings, undated (Box OS 3)
  - Paintings, watercolor, undated (Box OS 3)
  - Posters and prints, undated (Box OS 3)
  - Prints, undated (Box OS 3)
- Printed Materials, 1968-1983, 3 boxes
  Periodicals, pamphlets, and printed essays comprise this series. Subjects represented include feminism, Marxism, and art. A number of periodicals were removed from this collection and added to the Women's and LGBT Movements Periodicals collection. Materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Amazon Quarterly, Fall 1972 (Box 38)
  - Aphra: the Feminist Literary Magazine, Spring 1975 (Box 38)
  - Art, Architecture, and the Decorative Arts, 1983 (Box 38)
  - Art News, Jan. 1971, Oct. 1980, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Arts Magazine, Oct. 1977-Jan. 1978, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Atlantic Monthly, undated (Box 38)
  - Brief presented to the Royal Commission on the Status of Women in Canada, Bonnie Kreps, 1968 (Box 38)
  - A Documentary Herstory of Women Artists in Revolution, 1973 (Box 38)
  - Enter Fighting: Today's Woman, a Marxist-Leninist View, Clara Colon, 1970 (Box 38)
  - Every Woman, vol. 1, no. 9 (Box 38)
  - The Family: Revolutionary or Oppressive Force? by Caroline Lund, 1971 (Box 38)
  - Feminism and Marxism, Dorothy Ballan, 1971 (Box 38)
  - Fight on Sisters...and other Songs for Liberation, Carol Hanisch, 1978 (Box 38)
  - Four Women Living the Revolution: An Oral History of Contemporary Cuba, Oscar Lewis, et al., 1970 (Box 38)
  - Free Space: a Perspective on the Small Group in Women's Liberation, Pamela Allen, 1970 (Box 38)
  - Green Mountain Quarterly, Feb. 1976 (Box 38)
  - Hacker Art Books, Autumn 1995-Winter 1996 (Box 38)
  - Health Policy Advisory Center Bulletin, Mar. 1970 (Box 38)
  - Heresies: a Feminist Publication on Art and Politics, Jan., Fall 1977, Winter 1978, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Lectures on Liberation, Angela Y. Davis, circa 1970 (Box 38)
  - Leviathan, vol. 2, no. 1, May 1970 (Box 39)
  - Liberation, Sept.-Nov. 1971, Aug. 1972 (Box 39)
  - Liberation, Jan., May 1975 (Box 39)
  - Liberation Will Come From a Black Thing, James Forman, 1967 (Box 39)
  - Looking at Women: Poems by Fran Winant (Box 39)
  - Mademoiselle, Sept. 1969 (Box 39)
  - Meeting Ground, 1977-1980, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Mushroom Effect: A Directory of Women's Liberation, 1970 (Box 39)
  - The Myth of the Black Matriarchy, Robert Staples, 1970 (Box 39)
  - New York Feminist Manhattan Tribune, 1970 (Box 39)
  - off our backs, vol. 1, no. 7, 1970 Jun. 26 (Box 39)
  - On-the-Job Oppression of Working Women: A Collection of Articles, undated (Box 39)
  - Place of American Women: Economic Exploitation of Women, Joan Jordan, 1968 (Box 39)
  - Problems of Women's Liberation: A Marxist Approach, Evelyn Reed, 1969 (Box 39)
  - Protective Legislation, Joan Jordan, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Psychology Today, 1968 Apr. (Box 39)
  - Ramparts, 1970 Apr. (Box 39)
  - RAT, no. 20 (Box 39)
  - Red Herring, no. 2 (Box 39)
  - Redstockings press release, 1975 May 9 (Box 39)
  - Revolutionary Dynamics of Women's Liberation, George Novack, 1969 (Box 39)
  - The Second Page, no. 6, 1971 Nov. (Box 39)
  - The Second Wave, vol. 2, no. 2 (Box 39)
  - Sisterhood is Powerful, Betsey Stone, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Small pamphlets, circa 1969 (Box 39)
  - The Spokeswoman, vol. 2, no. 8, 1972 Feb. 1 (Box 39)
  - Teachers & Writers, 1979 (Box 39)
  - Times Change and with them Their Demands, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Tooth and Nail, Jan. 1970 (Box 39)
  - The Traffic in Women and other Essays on Feminism, Emma Goldman, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Vague, 1980 (Box 39)
  - Whole Woman, vol. 1, no. 2-3 (Box 40)
  - Witches, Midwives, and Nurses: A History of Women Healers, Barbara Ehrenreich and Deirdre English, undated (Box 40)
  - Woman's World, 1971 Apr. 15, 1971 July-August (Box 40)
  - Women: A Journal of Liberation, Fall 1970 (Box 40)
  - Women & Abortion: the Body as Battleground, Rosalyn Baxandall, 1992 (Box 40)
  - Women and Art, Winter 1971, Summer/Fall 1972 (Box 40)
  - Women in the Chinese Revolution, Laurie Landy, undated (Box 40)
  - Women in Health, Women's Work Project, undated (Box 40)
  - Women in Today's Economic Crisis, Women's Work Project, undated (Box 40)
  - Women on the Job: A Marxist-Leninist View, Judy Edelman, 1970 (Box 40)
  - Women under Attack: Abortion, Sterilization Abuse, and Reproductive Freedom, Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse, 1979 (Box 40)
  - The Women's Page, no. 3-4 (Box 40)
  - Women's Studies and the Arts, 1978 (Box 40)
  - Worker-Student Action Committees: France, May '68, R. Gregoire, F. Perlman (Box 40)
  - Working Women for Freedom, Angela Terrano, et al., 1976 (Box 40)
  - The Village Voice, 1968 June 6, Guardian, 1969 Mar. 29, Look, 1969 Dec. 16 (Box OS 1)
  - Daily World, 1969 Apr. 24, "Masculine Movement," New York Times, 1970 Aug. 27, "Women, Resistance, and Revolution," Books, 1973 May (Box OS 1)
  - The New York Times Magazine, 1970 Sept. 20-Oct. 25 (Box OS 1)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1969-1971, 1978-1980, 1991, and undated, 3 boxes
  Consists of audiocassettes and super 8 film documenting discussions, meetings, and other events. Items are labeled with original descriptions provided by Peslikis. Also included is a VHS tape of a memorial service for Peslikis.
  - Audiocassettes, 1970-1991; 1
    - Ann from South Africa, Anne Forer and Irene Peslikis, 1
      - Original audiocassette (Box 41, Audio-cassette RL01018-CS-0001)
    - Alix Kates Shulman and Irene Peslikis, Questions Re: Approach/Avoidance, 1979 Nov. 18, 2
      - Original audiocassette (Box 41, Audio-cassette RL01018-CS-0002)
    - Beverly, Irene, and Adrienne, 1980 Mar. 4, 3
      - Original audiocassette (Box 41, Audio-cassette RL01018-CS-0003)
    - Brooke and Irene, 1978-1979, 4
      - Original audiocassette (Box 41, Audio-cassette RL01018-CS-0004)
    - Community meeting, New York Feminist Art Institute, 1980 June 13, 5
      - Original audiocassette (Box 41, Audio-cassette RL01018-CS-0005)
    - Dad at home, 6
      - Original audiocassette (Box 41, Audio-cassette RL01018-CS-0006)
    - D.B., 1979 Dec. 6; R.R., 1979 Dec. 6 re: Army; Diane Wentwik, 7
      - Original audiocassette (Box 41, Audio-cassette RL01018-CS-0007)
    - Facing, 8
      - Original audiocassette (Box 41, Audio-cassette RL01018-CS-0008)
    - First class on Hegel, 9